创世之初 冥冥之中
In the beginning there was darkness,
随着一声爆炸
and then, bang--
诞生了无尽膨胀的
giving birth to an endless expanding existence
时间 空间和物质
of time, space, and matter.
每一天 新的发现都在揭秘这个诡异
Every day, new discoveries are unlocking the mysterious,
震撼 神秘莫测的
the mind-blowing, the deadly secrets
地方 - 我们所谓的《宇宙》
of a place we call "The Universe."
它们半路杀出 威胁我们的生存
They appear out of nowhere and threaten our very existence.
从闯入我们家园的石块
From rocks crashing through homes
到珠峰般大小的巨石引发大规模毁灭
to Mount Everest-sized boulders triggering mass annihilation,
没人能置身于它们的毒手之外
no one is safe from their wrath.
这些不速之客中的一些并非星际来客
And some of these intruders are not extraterrestrial.
它们实际上是人造宇宙垃圾
They're actually manmade cosmic junk.
我们所调查的陨石和太空碎片统称为
Take cover as we investigate meteorites and space debris--
从天而降的致命物体
the deadly stuff that falls from space.
--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://www.hdcmct.com
影片压制:暮云春树  字幕来源：HDC字幕组 调校：晴天 招募Q号: 76846146
历史频道 - 宇宙 第4季第3集 它从天而降
The History Channel - The Universe s04e03 It Fell From Space
亚利桑那州卡特里那巡天天文台
The Catalina Sky Observatory in Arizona
注意到了以前从未见到过的东西
notices something it hadn't seen before.
一颗大如旅行车的小行星正呼啸着奔向地球
An asteroid the size of an SUV is screaming down towards Earth
时速超过了2 7万英里
at over 27,000 miles per hour.
警报声响彻整个国际科学界
An alarm sounds throughout the international scientific community.
这颗小行星是否处在一路撞上地球呢？
Is this asteroid on a collision course with Earth?
这个对象非同寻常
This object was special
因为它可能会撞上地球
because it was probably going to impact the Earth,
在接下来的21小时行程中
and over the course of the next 21 hours,
500个观察数据产生于该对象试图精确计算出它的轨道
500 observations were made of the object to try to exactly calculate its orbit.
美国航天局喷气推进实验室
At NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory,
史蒂夫 切斯利接到了紧急叫醒电话
Steve Chesley gets the urgent wake-up call.
人人都想知道这块石头落地在何时何地
Everyone wants to know when and where this rock will touch ground.
他们给我发来了数据
They sent me the data.
我颇为激动地冲进办公室 在随后的两个小时里
I rushed into the office rather excitedly and spent the next couple of hours
全神贯注围绕着这个问题
trying to get my arms around the problem
运算数据
by running the numbers,
我得出结论 它有百分之百的撞击机会
and I reached the conclusion it was 100% chance of impact.
切斯利计算出撞击会在不足13个小时里发生
Chesley calculates the collision will occur in less than 13 hours,
大约是东非时间上午5 45
approximately 5:45 A.M. Eastern African time.
其目标 苏丹北部的努比亚沙漠
Its target: the Nubian Desert in northern Sudan.
我们没有真正预料或预计到
We hadn't really expected or anticipated
在撞击之前发现有小行星即将打击地球
the discovery of an asteroid that was going to hit the Earth before impact,
有时间回应和预测撞击的地点
with time to react and time to predict the location of the impact.
它非同寻常
It was very extraordinary.
以前从未见过
Never seen it before.
进入了撞击倒计时
It was countdown to impact.
已无时间去阻止这块失控的太空石头
With no time to stop this runaway space rock,
电邮发出去提醒地上 空中的人们
e-mails went out to alert those on the ground and in the air.
上午5:45
5:45 A.M.
那一刻已来到
The moment has arrived.
一位民航飞行员正飞经苏丹
A commercial pilot is flying over Sudan.
他目睹了一个火球闯入地球的大气层
He witnesses a fireball smack right into the Earth's atmosphere
其能量约为1000吨TNT
with the energy of about a thousand tons of TNT.
它一进入大气层就开始熊熊燃烧
As it entered the atmosphere, it started to burn and brighten.
某种意义上 对物体的压力会变得非常大
At some point, the stresses on the body became so fantastic
在大气压力下 它只有爆炸
from the atmospheric pressure that it just exploded.
爆炸听上去就像是音爆
That explosion would have sounded like a sonic boom.
地面上 其下方23英里处
On the ground, 23 miles below,
早祷告回家的苏丹人
Sudanese people returning from morning prayers
听到了可怕的轰鸣声
hear the frightening sonic roar.
目击者看到了一个闪亮的火球
Witnesses see a brilliant fireball,
拖着神秘的闪光划过天空
followed by mysterious flashes of light streak across the sky.
科学家希望该小行星的重量不足以
Scientists had hoped the asteroid wasn't heavy enough
完全穿透地球的大气层
to completely penetrate through the Earth's atmosphere
重创地面
and wreak havoc on the ground.
卫星跟踪了剧烈的爆炸
Satellites track the fiery explosion,
但是几乎没有迹象表明有任何碎片留下
but there is little indication that any fragments survive.
因此有可能
So there is a possibility
人们会受到这样的事件的惊吓
that people could be frightened by such an event,
不过这样小的东西所带来的伤害危险其实是非常低的
but the risk of injury is really very low from something so small.
史蒂夫是正确的
And Steve was correct.
没有伤亡及损失的报告
There were no reports of injuries or damage
因为碎片掉在了偏远地区
due to falling debris in the remote region.
行星地球逃过了一劫
Planet Earth was spared from a potential disaster
一定程度上是因为那里太偏远了并且撞击者也不大
partly because the region was so remote and the impactor was small.
然而故事并未就此结束
But the story doesn't end here.
2008年12月
December 2008.
天文学家彼得 詹尼斯肯斯组织了一支搜寻队
Astronomer Peter Jenniskens organizes a search and recovery team
来自苏丹的喀土穆大学
from the University of Khartoum in Sudan.
他决心找到不大可能的
He's determined to find the unlikely--
陨石
meteorites,
编号为2008TC3的小行星残留的碎片
the surviving fragments of the asteroid named 2008TC3.
我们有一车子的学生 他们都争相去搜寻
We had a busload of students who were all eager to go and search.
我们驱车29公里进入沙漠 来到靠近爆炸的地区
We drove 29 kilometers into the desert to go to the area close to the explosion
寻找可能幸存下来的小残片
to look for the smaller pieces that might have survived.
陨石猎人唯一的向导就是用来预测小行星的路径
The meteorite hunters' only guide is a map of the Nubian Desert
的努比亚沙漠地图
with the projected approach path of the asteroid.
他们基本上是利用我的轨迹
They basically used my trajectory
地面航迹 我已经布置在了
and the ground track that I had laid out
沙漠地面上了作为他们搜索的向导
on the desert floor as a guide for their search.
大家排成一行 间隔20 30码
Lined up everybody about 20, 30 yards apart,
然后成一直线走进沙漠
and then started walking down the desert in line,
搜寻黑色的东西
searching for things that were black.
不过要在岩质沙漠地面上发现很小的煤块状石头
But spotting small, charcoal-like stones on the rocky desert surface
无异于大海捞针
is akin to finding a needle in a haystack.
第一天太阳落山时
As the sun begins to set on the first day,
搜索队准备空手而归了
the team is about to walk away empty-handed
此时有个同学突然走向一块可疑的石头
when a student suddenly comes forward with a suspicious rock.
一个名叫穆罕默德 阿敏的同学
A student called Mohammed Alameen
手里拿着这块小石头 显然是块陨石
had this little rock in his hands that was clearly a meteorite.
它外面裹着一层漂亮的黑色熔凝壳
It had a beautiful black fusion crust around it,
无疑是一块陨石
and it was undoubtedly a meteorite.
于是大家群情激动
And then everybody started being excited
纷纷欢呼雀跃
and shouting and singing and waving their hands.
最终回收到280块陨石样本 总共有11磅
280 meteorite samples were eventually recovered, equaling 11 pounds,
这对行星科学家来说 就像是挖到了金矿
which, for planetary scientists, was like hitting paydirt.
这就是一块回收的陨石
This was one of the meteorites that was recovered,
没有比这更大的了
not much bigger than this.
我们认为大量的这些陨石
We think that a lot of these meteorites,
它们在爆炸时
when they came out of the explosion,
飞快地落下
were tumbling very rapidly,
那就导致了陨石在空中时就一路破碎了
and that resulted in breaking of the meteorites when they were still up in the air.
2008TC3是有史以来在太空中就被观察到的小行星
2008TC3 is the first asteroid ever observed in space
并后来在地面上所找到
which was later found on the ground.
科学家称其为首个小行星样本回收任务
Scientists are calling it the first asteroid sample return mission.
那是首次 我们在太空中发现了东西
It's the first time that we've actually detected something in space,
推断出它会击中地球
figured out that it was going to hit the Earth,
推断出它撞击地球的具体地点
figured out where it was going to hit the Earth,
并且我们居然看到它撞上了地球
and we actually saw it hit the Earth.
我们甚至还回收到了它的碎片
We've even recovered pieces of it.
真是了不起
That's remarkable.
这整个过程对我们来说确实了不起
This whole experience was really fantastic for us.
这是牛刀小试 让我们真正有所准备
This was an excellent test for what we're really preparing for,
就是有可能不得不面对未来的某个时刻
which is the possibility of having to deal with a larger impactor
更大的撞击
sometime in the future.
行星地球下一次可能就没这么幸运了
Planet Earth may not be so lucky the next time.
科学家现在怀疑
Scientists now suspect
2008TC3出自一块更大的石头
2008TC3 came from a piece of a much larger rock
它位于小行星带里 木星与火星之间的地带
from the asteroid belt, a region between Jupiter and Mars
那里是小行星 彗星的集聚地
where asteroids and comets take up residence.
在这个拥挤的星际街坊里
In this crowded galactic neighborhood,
这些太阳系形成时留下的遗老遗少
these fossil relics from the formation of the solar system
偶尔会相互碰撞 炸成小块
occasionally collide with each other and explode into smaller pieces.
就是这些碎片会往地球迁徙过来
It's these fragments that can migrate towards Earth.
子弹可以作为一个不错的替代物
A bullet can provide a pretty good stand-in
来说明一颗小行星打击另一颗小行星的撞击速度
for one asteroid striking another, in terms of its impact speed.
主小行星带里的小行星会相互碰撞
Asteroids in the main asteroid belt will run into each other
速度超过1 1万英里/小时
at speeds of over 11,000 miles per hour.
现在 飞出枪膛的子弹可以是那很好的比喻
Now, a bullet traveling out of a rifle can be a good analogy for that,
因为它们离开枪膛的速度 你知道 可能是那的五分之一
because they will leave a rifle barrel at speeds, you know, maybe a fifth that.
它不只是碎片
So it doesn't just fragment.
它把自己炸成了碎片
It literally blows itself to pieces.
我们会前往靶场
We'll head downrange
放置我们小小的人造小行星
and actually set up our little artificial asteroids
保持足够安全的距离进行射击
at a safe enough distance to shoot.
因为真正的小行星难以获得
Since real asteroids are hard to come by,
今天我们会用上这两个替身
we're going to use a couple of stand-ins today.
这些子弹的打击比作是
These bullet impacts are comparable
小行星带里的碰撞
to the collisions in the asteroid belt.
来看看我们这里的结果
Let's see what our results are here.
这其实是小行星撞击很典型的结果
This is actually rather typical of the results of an asteroid impact,
这里你往往会有几大块的碎片
where you tend to have a few large pieces of debris,
若干中等的碎片
several medium-size pieces.
不过大自然很善于制造出大量的小碎片
But nature is very good at making lots and lots of little debris.
这些千米级的小碎片
These little kilometer-sized fragments
就是我们现在所看到的近地小行星
are what we actually see today as the near-Earth asteroids,
这些碎片利用自己的门道
these fragments which have worked their way in
离开主小行星带
from the main asteroid belt,
逼近内太阳系
approaching the inner solar system,
掠过我们地球 有时会撞上我们的星球
passing near our planet, sometimes impacting our planet.
这些近地天体(NEOs)
These near-Earth objects, or NEOs,
已经将我们的近空间环境变成了一个危险地带
have transformed our near-space environment into a danger zone.
这些乱窜在内太阳系里的天体所具有的速度是 -
The speeds with which objects are running around in the inner solar system is--
它实际上极像是一串汽车
It's much akin to actually a bunch of cars
在高速公路上狂飙
driving crazily down a highway.
这些汽车本身在高速行驶
The vehicles themselves are traveling at high speeds.
一旦它们盲目越线
When they cross lanes without looking
也许会相互碰撞
and perhaps running into each other,
其撞击速度同样很高
they're hitting at equally high speeds.
这有点像在各自独立轨道上
And that's kind of like objects moving on their own independent orbits
绕太阳运行的天体
around the Sun.
每隔数百年
Every few hundred years,
地球就会遭遇到足球场般大的石头的打击
Earth gets hit with rocks the size of a football field
可以摧毁整座城市
that can destroy entire cities.
但是每隔50万年
But every half million years,
我们就会遭遇大山般大的巨石的撞击
we get struck with boulders the size of mountains
可以引发全球性灾难
that could ignite global disasters.
地球大气层 一层包围我们星球的大气
The Earth's atmosphere, a layer of gases surrounding our planet,
会焚烧掉大部分材料
incinerates most material,
但是偶尔 较大较沉的天体会漏网而过
but, occasionally, larger, heavier objects slip through.
一旦它们进入地球的大气层
As soon as they enter the Earth's atmosphere,
它们就会慢下来 被大气层减缓速度
they get slowed down, decelerated by the atmosphere,
它们几乎会失去它们进入时的速度
and they lose pretty much all of the velocity with which they entered,
那段时间就是你看到火球事件的时候
and during that time is when you see the fireball event,
但是它们一旦失去其进入时的速度
but once they lose that velocity that they came in with,
就基本上差不多以末端速度
they essentially just fall pretty much at terminal velocity
降落到地面上
onto the Earth's surface.
小行星撞击地球大气层时
When asteroids hit the Earth's atmosphere,
成为了流星 闪亮的火球划过天空
they become meteors, bright fireballs in the sky.
如果它们落在地上 就称为陨石
If they make it to the ground, they're called meteorites.
仅过去的一个世纪里
Over the past century alone,
陨石就已经击中过房屋 车辆 甚至人
meteorites have struck homes, vehicles, and even people.
1954年 一颗8磅的陨石
In 1954, an eight-pound meteorite
冲破了阿拉巴马州锡拉科加的一个房顶
crashed through the roof of a home in Sylacauga, Alabama,
击中了一位女士的屁股 给她留下了讨厌的疤痕
and hit a woman in the hip, leaving her with nasty bruises.
1992年10月 业余视频捕捉到一个火球
In October 1992, amateur videos caught a fireball
划过几个大西洋州的天空
flashing across the skies above several Atlantic states.
27磅重的陨石最终击碎了纽约皮克斯基尔的
The 27-pound meteorite eventually crushed the back end of a car
一辆汽车的车尾
in Peekskill, New York.
2008年11月 一架警用抓拍摄像机
In November 2008, a police dash camera
录制到了加拿大阿尔伯塔省上空一次明亮的陨石爆炸
recorded a bright meteorite explosion in the skies over Alberta, Canada.
这些视频上捕捉到的撞击
These caught-on-video impacts
证明了确实有东西从天而降
prove that things really do fall from the sky.
尤为震惊的
What's even more startling
是更大撞击的实物证据
is the physical evidence of much bigger impacts,
那些造成了过去的全球性灾难的
ones that have caused global catastrophes in the past
以及有可能引发未来的宇宙末日的证据
and may ignite a cosmic Armageddon in the future.
地球并非一直是人类的理想住所
Earth was not always an ideal address for human beings.
在其襁褓时期 38亿年前
During its infancy, 3.8 billion years ago,
太阳的第三块大石头身处宇宙战区内
the third rock from the Sun was a cosmic war zone.
在这个叫做后期重轰炸期的短时期内
During this brief period, called the Late Heavy Bombardment,
数十亿个太阳系形成时留下的碎片
billions of leftover debris from the formation of the solar system
狂轰滥炸我们地球 其频率比现在高出了2万倍
pummeled our planet at rates up to 20,000 times higher than today.
当时的情况是木星和土星
What happened is that Jupiter and Saturn,
我们太阳系里的两颗大行星
the two giant planets in our solar system,
进入了彼此之间所谓的引力共振
went into what's called a gravitational resonance with one another,
结果木星围绕太阳走完整整两圈
so Jupiter made two complete orbits around the Sun
土星才走完一圈
for every single orbit made by Saturn,
此时 就重新安排了整个太阳系
and when that happened, it rearranged the entire solar system.
它重新配置了天王星 海王星 木星和土星
It reshuffled Uranus, Neptune, Jupiter, and Saturn,
把大行星往外搬了出去
and moved the giant planets farther out.
结果把一连串彗星和小行星
When that happened, that just sent a volley of comets and asteroids
射入了内太阳系
rocketing into the inner solar system.
同时 那些石头天体
At the same time, these rocky bodies
帮助把我们的幼年星球塑造成了今天的模样
helped to mold our baby planet to the shape it is today.
这些就是交战的疤痕
Here are the battle scars.
地球上只有170个撞击坑还依然可辨
Only 170 impact craters are still visible on Earth.
天气 水 板块构造
Weather, water, and plate tectonics
抹去了古代宇宙暴力事件大多数痕迹
have erased most traces of ancient cosmic violence.
但是地球动荡的过去的证据就在月球上
But proof of Earth's tumultuous past lies on the Moon,
它形成于同一个时期
which was formed at the same time,
但是缺少了板块构造和其他侵蚀过程
but lacks plate tectonics and other erosion processes
去抹去那些证据
that tend to erase the evidence.
地球本身遭遇到的轰击
The Earth itself has been bombarded
也每每击中我们邻近的月球
every bit as much as our nearby Moon.
你如果抬头仰望空中的明月
If you look up at the Moon in the sky
会看到它伤痕累累的月面
and you see its cratered surface,
你须想到我们的地球
you have to imagine our own Earth
受到的创伤和打击至少是那种程度
cratered and battered to at least that degree,
事实上 因为我们是太空中一个更大的目标
and in fact, because we're a bigger target in space, even more.
通过计算月球上的陨石坑
By counting craters on the Moon,
科学家可以了解到地球附近古往今来
scientists can learn about the number of impacts
所受撞击的数量
on the nearby Earth, past and present.
科学家可以了解到撞击地球的小行星的
Scientists can learn about the sizes and compositions of asteroids
大小及成分
that impact the Earth
通过研究其产生的陨石坑的特征
by studying the characteristics of the craters that they create.
我们今天要来演示一下
So we're going to try and demonstrate that today
投掷一些重物在这里的沙滩上
by tossing some weights into the sand on the beach here,
我们要看看能否找出重物大小
and we're going to see if we can come up with a relationship
与其创造的弹坑之间的关系
between the size of the weight and the size of the crater that it creates.
根据我的测量
Based on my measurements,
我计算出在这个海滩上的撞击 有三块石头
I calculate that this beach was impacted by three rocks
直径在10英寸
10 inches in diameter,
5块石头直径6英寸
five rocks that were 6 inches in diameter,
还有11块2英寸的石头
and 112-inch diameter rocks.
这种测量海滩上弹坑大小及频率的技术
This technique of measuring the size and frequency of craters on this beach
非常类似于科学家用来了解地球历史上
is very similar to the technique that scientists use
发生撞击的频率的技术
to understand the frequency of impacts throughout Earth's history.
现在 保存完好的陨石坑
Today, the best-preserved impact craters
存在于世界各地的沙漠地区
exist in dry desert regions around the world.
流星陨石坑 位于亚利桑那州的温斯洛附近
Meteor Crater, located near Winslow, Arizona,
是太空物体造成的破坏永久的纪念之一
is one of the lasting reminders of the destruction caused by objects from space,
科学家才揭开表象
and scientists are just cracking the surface
去了解这些暴力事件的后果
of understanding the repercussions of these ferocious events.
好 点火
Okay, lights.
我们是不是要回到25万？
Okay, do we want to back one off to 250,000?
行星地质学家皮特 舒尔茨构思了一项新实验
Planetary geologist Pete Schultz formulated a new experiment
模拟陨石坑在表象下的情形
to simulate what impact craters look like under the surface.
1 1英尺
It's 1.1 feet.
在美国宇航局艾姆斯研究中心的垂直射击靶场
At the Vertical Gun Range at NASA's Ames Research Center,
舒尔茨正利用一支巨大的30口径的轻气炮
Schultz is using a massive 30-caliber light-gas gun
在真空室里将弹丸射向各种靶子
that shoots projectiles at various targets inside a vacuum chamber.
今天 我们要来一探究竟弹坑形成时的情形
Today, we're going to try to look inside a crater as it forms,
为此 我们要用上一块透明体
and to do this, we're going to use a clear block.
它是透明的
It's transparent,
因此我们实际上可以看到弹坑的成长过程
so we actually get to watch the crater as it grows,
是从内部 而不是从外部
but from the inside, rather than from the outside.
这颗小珠子模拟
This little bead is simulating
撞击地球表面的小行星
an asteroid that's going to slam into the surface of the Earth,
我们这就进去
so let's get inside.
我们进入了撞击室
We're in the impact chamber.
一切就发生在这里
This is where everything happens.
子弹小珠子的射入速度
The little projectile bead is going to be coming in
将在每秒4英里左右
at around four miles per second.
我们将击中这块透明体
We're going to hammer this transparent block.
我们将观察小行星击中地表时
We're going to be looking at everything that happens below the ground
地下所发生的一切
when that asteroid hits the surface of the Earth.
在真空室外 高速摄影机
Outside the chamber, high-speed cameras
会从不同角度记录到深度撞击
will document the deep impact from various angles.
岛津(分析仪)都就位了吗？
Are the Shimadzus all up down there?
在控制室里
In the control room,
舒尔茨神情紧张地看着屏幕
Schultz watches the monitor with nervous anticipation.
高压
High voltage.
垂直炮将玻璃弹珠射入亚克力块
The vertical gun launches the glass bead projectile into the acrylic block.
好极了 哇
Sweet. Wow. Okay.
实在是太漂亮了
That is just frickin' gorgeous.
实验获得了巨大的成功
The experiment was a smashing success.
哇塞 这里我们实际上有了撞击
Kapow. So, here we actually have the impact,
不过我们现在看到了这个蒸汽柱
but now we see this vapor plume.
那其实是高温气流
This is really hot gas.
其温度接近太阳表面
It's about a temperature close to the surface of the Sun,
随着它到了外面 就冷却了
and then as it moves away, it cools,
现在我们开始形成了有喷发物的弹坑
and now we begin to form the crater with the ejecta coming out.
我们现在看到了弹坑开始形成的内部情形
And we're now watching the crater actually begin to form on the inside.
棒极了
That is awesome.
我想看看我们的结果
Okay, I want to see what we did.
哦 天哪 我们居然把这破坏了
Oh, man, did we bust this up.
现在我们可以看到这些破碎的整个发展过程
Now we can look to see how these cracks develop through time,
如果这是个大碰撞 这些破碎会发展到
so if this were a big impact, these cracks would grow
整个弹坑随后会向内塌落
where the entire crater could then collapse inward and fail.
垂直射击靶场的撞击试验
Impact experiments at the Vertical Gun Range
清楚地表明了从天而降的小行星
shed light on the large-scale destruction
所造成的大规模破坏
caused by asteroids that have fallen from space.
我们看到的撞击 不光是裂缝与开裂
When we see an impact, it's not just the cracks and cracking.
你还会看到蒸汽羽状爆扩
You will also see the vapor plume expanding.
那会影响到生命 影响到生存
That affects life. That affects survival.
如果这种撞击发生在地球上 具有较大规模的话
If this impact occurred on Earth and was large in scale,
就只会煎熬大气
it would simply fry the atmosphere.
会飞出碎片 并随之再次打击地球
It would send debris out, and as it hits the Earth again,
就会引发更多的破坏
it would cause more devastation.
科学家已经发现 来自太空的撞击
Scientists have discovered that impacts from space
已经影响到了地球生命的演变
have affected the evolution of life on Earth.
我们知道 事实上 打击地球的陨石流量
We know that, in fact, the flux of meteorites hitting the Earth
过去要比今天大很多
was much higher in the past than it is today,
事实上 一直有这方面的例子
and, in fact, there have been known instances,
比如 6500万年前的大撞击事件
for example, the large impact event 65 million years ago
发生在白垩纪-第三纪之交
at the Cretaceous-Tertiary boundary.
6500万年前 一颗大如珠峰的小行星
65 million years ago, an asteroid the size of Mount Everest
击中了墨西哥的尤卡坦半岛
struck the Yucatan Peninsula in Mexico
具有1亿颗兆吨级原子弹的当量
with the energy of a 100-million-megaton bomb.
它在水下形成了一个上百英里宽的弹坑
It created a hundred-mile-wide crater underwater
最终在1980年代被发现了
that was finally discovered in the 1980s.
科学家已确定
Scientists have determined
该小行星撞击点燃大气层的事件
that the asteroid impact ignited atmospheric events
可能导致了75％的史前物种的大灭绝
that may have led to the mass extinction
其中包括恐龙
of 75% of all prehistoric species, including the dinosaurs.
有大量的潜在影响会导致灭绝
There were a lot of potential effects that could've led to the extinctions.
加热大气层 比如 由喷射物
Heating of the atmosphere, for instance, by the ejecta,
或许会引发山火
perhaps leading to wildfires,
大气的毒化
the poisoning of the atmosphere
来自小行星蒸发所产生的气体
from the gases produced from the vaporized asteroid.
每一个生态灾难 你都可以想到会同时发生
It was every ecological disaster you could think of all happening at the same time.
然而这是否是最后一次小行星引发大灭绝呢？
But was this the last time an asteroid triggered a mass extinction?
一个有争议的新理论认为一块太空石头是
A controversial new theory suggests a space rock was responsible
冰河时期北美大型哺乳动物的消失的罪魁祸首
for the disappearance of the Ice Age mega-mammals of North America.
科学家渴望知道1 3万年前所发生的事情
Scientists are dying to know what happened 13,000 years ago.
冰河时期正缓慢结束
The Ice Age was slowly ending.
北美大陆居住有巨兽
The North American continent was inhabited with big beasts
如猛犸象
like the woolly mammoth,
乳齿象
mastodon,
巨型地懒
giant ground sloth,
以及短脸熊
and the short-faced bear,
但是某东西造成了35个主要物种
but something caused 35 major groupings of species
从化石记录中消失了
to vanish from the fossil record.
许多人认为古克洛维斯人
Many think the ancient Clovis people,
一个狩猎人种 消灭了这些巨型哺乳动物
a hunter and gatherer society, killed off the mega-mammals.
但是令人震惊的新证据表明 一个从天而降的物体
But startling new evidence suggests that an object from space
有可能导致了这些举行动物的灭亡
may have led to the demise of the giant creatures.
1 3万年前
13,000 years ago,
气候突然迅速地戏剧性改变
the climate changed suddenly, rapidly, and dramatically.
貌似有某种外星事件
It looks like there was some type of extraterrestrial event,
没准是大陨石
whether it was a large meteorite,
小行星 或是彗星在大气层中爆炸
an asteroid, or a comet exploding in the atmosphere,
突然之间
and all of a sudden,
地球被抛回了小冰河时期
the planet was thrown back into a little Ice Age.
北美短期重新经历了一场冰河环境
North America experienced a brief return to Ice Age conditions.
那么这种寒流与巨型动物消失之间
So could there be a connection between this cold snap
会不会有所联系呢？
and the disappearance of the mega-mammals?
考古学家肯 坦克斯利声称已发掘到了
Archeologist Ken Tankersley claims to have dug up evidence
宇宙撞击可能的证据
of a possible cosmic impact in Sheridan Cave,
是在俄亥俄州凯里的谢里登洞穴里
located in Carey, Ohio.
来看看你都发现了什么
Let's see what you found so far.
这是仅有的12个已知的地点之一 可以精确追溯
It's one of only 12 known sites that have been precisely dated
晚更新世的灭绝时间
to the time of the late Pleistocene extinction,
就是最后一次冰河时期的结束时
which was the end of the last Ice Age.
在这个深邃的洞穴里 坦克斯利和他的小组
In this deep cavern, Tankersley and his team
发现了那个时期的
have discovered the burned remains of
60多个动植物种的焚烧遗骸
more than 60 species of plants and animals from that time period,
包括克洛维斯文化的狩猎武器
including hunting weapons of the Clovis culture.
我难以相信
I don't believe it.
这是克洛维斯人的骨矛
This is a Clovis bone point.
它是用巨型哺乳动物的肋骨做成的
It's manufactured from a mega-mammal rib,
或许就是美洲乳齿象之类的大型动物
probably a large animal such as the American mastodon.
这个标本的迷人之处
What's fascinating about this specimen
在于制作之人
is the person who manufactured this
可能目睹了1 3万年前的事件
likely witnessed the event 13,000 years ago.
坦克斯利说 他发掘出来的大部分骨骸
Tankersley says that most of the bones he's uncovered
都经历了剧烈的燃烧
underwent intense burning
那不可能仅仅是森林大火所造成的
that couldn't have been caused by a mere forest fire.
他说必定是来自巨大的爆炸
He says it had to have been from a colossal explosion,
诸如地球撞击所造成的
the kind generated by an Earth impact.
考古学家称他找到了确凿的证据
And the archeologist says he's found the smoking gun.
来看看我们这里的东西
Well, look what we have here.
它隐藏在叫做"黑垫层"的黑色的地质土层里
It's hidden in a dark geological layer of dirt called the "black mat,"
可以追溯到1 29万年前
which dates back to 12,900 years ago.
这种土层已经在北美发现有50多处
This layer has been uncovered in more than 50 locations in North America.
请留意这个黑色区域
Note this black area.
来看看我是否能铲除这里
Let's see if I can trowel through here,
带出一些较黑的土层
bring out some of the more dark areas.
噢 不错
Oh, nice.
我们确实在这个地方 看到了最后一次
We're literally, at this spot, looking at the contact
冰河时期的交汇点
of the end of the last Ice Age,
这层氧化层在其上方
and this oxidized layer above it,
这里就是大型哺乳动物灭绝的地方
this is where the mega-mammals go extinct.
在这层沉积层里
Within this sediment layer,
一些科学家声称已经找到了关键的证据
some scientists claim to have found key pieces of evidence
直指一个宇宙撞击事件
that point to a cosmic impact.
碳球粒 产生于大火
Carbon spherules, created by intense fires,
钻石 形成于极端的温度和压力下
shocked diamonds, formed through extreme temperatures and pressures,
六方金刚石 罕见的六角型钻石
Ionsdaleites, rare hexagonal-shaped diamonds
只见于陨石中
that are only found in meteorites,
微流星
and micrometeorites,
来自外太空的铁镍微粒
minuscule pieces of iron and nickel that come from outer space.
如果我们拿上一块磁铁 划过这层氧化层
If we take a magnet and run it across this oxidized layer,
我想我们会吸到一些陨石微粒
my guess is we'll probably pick up micrometeorites.
你可以看到沉积物的吸附性
You can see how the sediment's adhering.
就像磁铁从这土层里吸到铁一样
And just as the magnet picks up iron from this layer,
磁铁也会吸附到这块陨石上
so does the magnet adhere to this meteorite,
这就表明 因为我们在这一层里
and this suggests, because we have
有高浓度的微流星体
a high concentration of micrometeorites in this layer
上下方则完全不存在
and a complete absence above or below,
那是1 3万年前的事件
and it's at the event of 13,000 years ago,
戏剧性的事情发生在了这里
something dramatic occurred here.
我们知道整个北美地区
We know that all over North America,
曾有过一层薄薄的尘埃粒子层
there was a thin layer of dust and particles
就在黑垫层形成之前
just before that black mat formed.
那就表明 事情就发生在
That indicates that something happened
该事件之前 就是气候变化之前
right before the event that is the climatic change.
那是什么？
What is it?
我们仍然不知究竟
We still don't know exactly.
我们所知的一切就是发生了什么
All we know is that something happened.
迄今为止 尚没有陨石坑发现
To date, no impact crater has been found,
不过太空石头比一定要到达地面
but a space rock doesn't have to reach the ground
导致大规模的灭绝
to generate mass devastation.
1908年 一块石头闯入大气层
In 1908, a rocky body slammed into the atmosphere
在西伯利亚通古斯荒野上空6英里
six miles above Siberia's Tunguska wilderness.
释放的能量相当于5兆吨TNT炸药
It released energy yielding about five megatons of TNT.
你可以想象 其感觉就像是一个大肚子跳下高台
You can imagine what it feels like to do a belly flop off of a high diving board
拍打进水中
and you smack into the water.
弱小的石质小行星也会经受类似的感觉
A small, weak, rocky asteroid will kind of undergo a similar sort of feeling
它很快减速
as it very quickly is decelerated
阻力来自稠密的低层大气
and brakes in the dense lower atmosphere.
紧接着通古斯的空爆
Immediately after the Tunguska airburst impact,
强烈的冲击波和热气浪
an intense shockwave and hot air blast
扑向地面 向外扩展
traveled to the ground and spread outward.
它吞噬了近1000平方英里的森林
It engulfed almost 1,000 square miles of forest.
有些科学家提出一个类似的情景
Some scientists propose that a similar scenario
可能促成了北美大型哺乳动物的灭绝
may have contributed to the extinction of the North American mega-mammals,
一颗彗星 而不是小行星 可能就是罪魁祸首
and a comet, not an asteroid, may have been the culprit.
与小行星不同 这些肮脏的雪球
Unlike asteroids, these dirty snowballs
裹挟着较多的冰与气体 往往在抵达地面前
contain more ices and gases that tend to break up
就支离破碎了
before reaching the surface.
理论上彗星闯入地球时
When the theorized comet came down into the Earth
会在大气层里爆炸
and would have exploded in the atmosphere,
会散布喷射物 产生在它的下方
it would have distributed amongst the ejecta that was created beneath it.
也会看到其留下的沉积物里有巨大的变化
It would also have seen a great variation in the deposits left behind.
会在很大的区域里有剧烈的焚烧
There would have been intense burning over a large area.
撞击区里的一切 当然
Anything within the impact zone, of course,
会被彻底毁灭
would have been devastating.
同时 不管怎样
At the same time, however,
它不会直接冲击到世界其他地方
it would not have had immediate impact for the rest of the planet,
只是撞击区本身里面
just within the impact area itself.
这个所谓的克洛维斯彗星理论认为深刻的气候变化
This so-called Clovis Comet Theory suggests that profound climate changes
导致了北美猛犸象的最终灭绝
led to the eventual extinction of the mammoths from North America.
然而 与普遍共识相左的是
However, contrary to popular belief,
有少量确实存活在世界的若干地区
a small number actually survived in various regions of the world
一直到公元2000年前后
up until around 2000 B.C.
考古证据表明克洛维斯文化并没有
And archaeological evidence indicates that the Clovis culture didn't go extinct
从这个所谓的撞击走向消亡
from this alleged impact.
相反 他们适应了不断变化的环境
Rather, they adapted to their changing environment.
在克洛维斯人狩猎的大型猎物
When the large game animals that Clovis people were hunting
从地平线上消失后
disappeared from the landscape,
人们不得不改变狩猎的方法
people had to change the way in which they were hunting and gathering.
我们也许永远都无法确切知道
We may never know with certainty
是否是近地彗星造成了克洛维斯事件
whether a near-Earth comet caused the Clovis event,
不过现代人会学会地球撞击后的幸存吗？
but would modern man learn to survive after an Earth impact?
我们可能最终将经受考验
We may eventually be put to the test.
在这个非常时刻 陨石科学家踏破铁鞋
At this very moment, meteorite scientists scour the landscape
寻觅着这些从天而降的信使
in search of these messengers from the sky.
这些太空石头掌握着过去撞击的线索
These space rocks hold clues to impacts of the past,
同时科学家现在发现
and as scientists are now discovering,
还有未来行将发生的线索
clues to what is coming in the future.
大规模灭绝
Mass extinctions,
数英里宽的弹坑
mile-wide craters,
烧焦的地景 -
scorched landscapes--
通通是太空来物造成的
all created by objects from space.
陨石一直在侵扰我们的星球
Meteorites have been intruding on our planet
自太阳系形成时就开始了
since the formation of the solar system.
那么我们通常是在哪里找到这些石头的呢？
So where do we typically find these rocks?
多数陨石 较容易在地球的沙漠地区找到
Most meteorites, they're more easily found in dry desert regions of the Earth,
比如 撒哈拉大沙漠
for example, in the Saharan Desert
乃至南极那样的寒冷沙漠地区
or even the cold deserts like Antarctica,
没有大量植被的地方
where there's not a whole lot of vegetation
或没有大量其他石头来迷惑你的地方
or there's not a whole lot of other rocks to confuse you.
不过 陨石降落 全球各地是机会均等的
However, meteorites fall everywhere on Earth with equal probability.
宇宙化学家沃德瓦
Cosmo-chemist Meenakshi Wadhwa
曾周游世界搜寻陨石 现在监管着
has traveled the world in search of meteorites and now oversees
世界上最大的大学陨石收藏
the largest university-based meteorite collection in the world.
我们现在看到的陨石收藏
We're here looking at the collection of meteorites
属于亚利桑那州立大学陨石研究中心
in the Center for Meteorite Studies at Arizona State University.
基本上有三种不同种类的陨石
There's basically three different kinds of meteorites.
你可以看到石质陨石
You can have stony meteorites,
石-铁陨石 或铁陨石
stony-iron, or iron-rich meteorites.
不过所有这三种至少都含有一些金属
But all three kinds have at least some amount of metal.
你分辨地球岩石和陨石可以通过
And so you can distinguish terrestrial rocks
陨石里的金属含量
from meteorites by the content of metal in meteorites.
区分陨石与地球岩石的另一个方法
The other way to actually distinguish a meteorite from a terrestrial rock
就是你会看到陨石有一层熔壳
is that you'll actually see a fusion crust on meteorites
是这些物体坠入地球大气层时形成的
that forms on these objects when they're falling through the Earth's atmosphere.
所回收的大部分陨石
Most of the meteorites recovered
都源自火星与木星之间的小行星带
originated in the asteroid belt between Jupiter and Mars.
不过有近四打实际上是来自我们的月球
But nearly four dozen actually came from our Moon
和火星
and the planet Mars.
想法是你或许有
The idea there is that you probably had
一个大的流星体撞击月球或火星
a large asteroidal body that impacted the Moon or Mars
喷发出月球或火星的外层碎片
and ejected pieces of the crust of the Moon or Mars,
这些喷发物或许就落入了
and these ejected pieces probably fell
这些摇摆不定的与地球相交的轨道
into these unstable Earth-crossing orbits,
最终碎片与地球殊途同归了
and eventually pieces made their way to the Earth that way.
这是一块月球陨石
This is a piece of a lunar meteorite,
我们认为它来自月球的高原部分
and we believe it came from the highlands portion of the Moon.
我们知道这实际上是月球陨石
And we know that this is actually a lunar meteorite
因为我们可以将其比对实际样本
because we can compare this with actual samples
那是阿波罗任务在60年代末 70年代初
that were brought back by the Apollo missions
带回来的
in the late sixties and early seventies.
陨石是珍贵的研究对象
Meteorites are precious research subjects.
尽管它们一而再 再而三地摧毁生命
Although they've destroyed life time and time again,
但是它们或许也带来了地球生命所需的化学物质
they may also have provided the chemicals needed for life on Earth.
这或许是世上研究最充分的陨石
This is possibly one of the most well-studied meteorites in the world.
它于1969年落在了墨西哥
It fell in 1969 in Mexico.
对这块石头需要注意的一个有趣之处
And an interesting thing to note about this rock
就是这些白色颗粒可能是一些我们太阳系形成时
is that these white grains are possibly some of the oldest solids
的最古老的固体
that formed in our solar system
是我们太阳系45亿年前形成时的
as our solar system was forming 4 1/2 billion years ago.
这些白色颗粒 含有地球的大气化学物质
These white grains, combined with the atmospheric chemicals
和有机化合物
and organic compounds on Earth,
或许已经形成了氨基酸的混合物
may have formed a mixture of amino acids,
生命的基本要素
the essential elements of life.
因此陨石扮演了一个非常重要的角色
So meteorites have played a very important role
或许就在我们星球生命的形成中
in possibly the formation of life on our planet
当然还有我们星球生命的进化中
and certainly the evolution of life on our planet.
陨石或许曾经为生命提供了必要的要素
Meteorites may have once provided the necessary components for living things.
但是它们也可能是攸关生死的源头
But they can be a source of grave concern
一旦它们从天而降 毫无预警的话
when they hurtle down from space without prior warning.
一个熊熊燃烧的陨石从天而降
A fiery meteorite streaked down from the sky
撞击了秘鲁小镇Carancas附近的松软的土壤
and impacted the soft soil near the Peruvian town of Carancas,
靠近玻利维亚边境
which borders Bolivia.
碎片飞出600英尺
Debris flew over 600 feet
同时陨石留下了一个弹坑 宽15码 深15英尺
as the meteorite left a crater over 15 yards wide and 15 feet deep.
当时有一位男士骑车经过
There was a gentleman riding a bicycle,
被掀翻在地
and he was knocked over.
另一个人在看另一个方向
Another person looking in the other direction
猛一回头 看这东西落下
quickly turned around and saw this thing hit
随后升起巨大的羽状物
with a large plume rising above.
在与当地的村民交流中
In talking with the locals, the villagers,
他们一头雾水 只是认为
they had no idea, except they thought
或许这是某种军事行动
maybe this was some form of military action.
你知道的 他们非常靠近玻利维亚边境
You know, they're very close to the border of Bolivia.
科学家安慰当地人说那是一颗陨石
Scientists reassured the locals that a meteorite,
不是导弹造成的撞击坑
and not a missile, caused the impact crater.
然而紧接着事件的发生
But immediately after the event,
许多村民抱怨说头痛和呕吐
many villagers complained about headaches and vomiting.
他们确实生病了 极有可能是因为硫
They literally became ill, most likely because of sulfur
或因为微粒的吸入
or because of the fine dust that was inhaled.
蒸发物或许是来自陨石降落时
The vapors probably came from the material
紧随其后的物质
that was following the meteorite as it was coming through.
它穿越大气层时 边熔化 边蒸发
It was melting, it was vaporizing as it passed through the atmosphere.
很有可能在其撞击时 引发了额外的气体释放
And it probably, when it hit, caused an additional release of gas.
那么太空石头会不会把有害元素送到地球来呢？
But could a space rock actually deliver harmful elements to Earth?
科幻电影和阴谋论者
Sci-fi movies and conspiracy theorists
提出过陨石对我们星球播下
have proposed that meteorites could seed our planet
致命的细菌或病毒
with lethal bacteria or viruses.
然而真假如何呢？
But what's fact and what's fiction?
其发生的概率微乎其微
The probability of this happening is very, very, very small.
如果石头带它来到地球
If that rock made it to Earth
也就是存在有微生物
and somehow that microbial life form survived,
它会发现我们的大气层很毒
it would find our atmosphere very toxic.
任何微生物进化在厌氧环境中
Any microbe that evolved in an anaerobic,
无氧环境中
in a non-oxygen environment,
都不可能在氧气中长期存活
is not going to survive long in oxygen.
秘鲁陨石挑起
The possibility that the Peruvian meteorite
宇宙生物战的可能性微乎其微
committed cosmic biological warfare is remote.
不过这块撞击附近村庄的小石陨石带来的
But had this small stony meteorite impacted a nearby village,
后果将会是全然不同的
the aftermath would have been much different.
这看上去就像是有人安放了一颗路边炸弹
This would look like somebody had planted a roadside bomb.
它会是那种效果
It would've had that effect.
它炸开的洞非常之大
It opened up a hole so large
可以吞下几辆汽车
that it would have swallowed several cars.
秘鲁陨石撞击
The Peruvian meteorite impact
再次表明了天上掉下的东西神秘莫测
once again illustrates the unpredictability of things that fall from the heavens.
太空石头并非可以导致人体伤害的唯一物体
And space rocks aren't the only objects that can cause bodily harm.
每年有多达200个重物打击我们的星球
Up to 200 heavy objects hit our planet each year,
它们不是天外之物
and they're not extraterrestrial.
它们是人造的
They're manmade.
哥伦比亚号航天飞机
The space shuttle Columbia
在行将结束其太空使命时灾难降临了
was about to conclude its mission in space when disaster struck.
飞行器在重返地球大气层时解体了
The vehicle disintegrated during re-entry into Earth's atmosphere.
碎片落在了得克萨斯州 路易斯安那州和阿肯色州
Debris fell over Texas, Louisiana, and Arkansas.
7名宇航员全部遇难
All seven crew members perished.
由于重返时的加热
Because of re-entry heating,
在进入大气层后温度越来越高
it got hotter as it came into the atmosphere,
一些关键部件发生了故障
some critical components failed.
那引发了整个航天飞机的整体完蛋
That caused an overall failure of the entire spacecraft,
碎片散落在一个很大的区域
which spread debris over a large footprint.
航天飞机的重返灾难十分罕见 但是太空碎片并不罕见
Spacecraft re-entry disasters are rare, but space debris is not.
自太空时代开启以来
Since the beginning of the Space Age,
火箭已经携带了数以千计的卫星
rockets have carried thousands of satellites
进入绕地轨道
into orbits around our planet.
结果 我们丢弃在太空中
As a result, we've littered space
有用过的火箭级 报废的卫星 燃料罐
with spent rocket stages, defunct satellites, fuel tanks,
以及碎片之间碰撞和爆炸所产生的
as well as nuts, bolts, and fragments from collisions
螺母 螺栓和碎片
and explosions with other debris.
这些被遗弃的太空垃圾盘旋在我们星球上空
This abandoned space debris hovers over our planet
宛如宇宙垃圾场
like a cosmic garbage dump,
有些最终会掉回到地球上
and some will eventually fall back to the Earth.
问题是何时何地？
The question is when and where?
重返大气层的物体 确实具有风险
Things that re-enter the atmosphere, they do have a risk.
真正的风险在于物体穿过大气层
The real risk is that something falling through the atmosphere
会击中地面上的人
will hit a person on the ground.
5400吨太空垃圾已经砸向了地球
5,400 tons of space junk has already crash-landed on Earth.
1979年 太空实验室 第一个空间站
In 1979, Skylab, the first space station,
碎片散落在印度洋
scattered debris across the Indian Ocean
及澳洲部分地区
and parts of Australia.
1997年 一块DVD大小的冒烟的金属碎片从云端落下
In 1997, a DVD-sized piece of smoldering metal fell from the clouds
与俄克拉荷马州塔尔萨的一位女士擦肩而过
and brushed the shoulder of a woman near Tulsa, Oklahoma.
她没有受伤
She wasn't injured,
但是千里之外 这个570磅重的不锈钢罐
but hundreds of miles away, this 570-pound stainless steel tank
落在了得克萨斯州一座农舍的旁边
landed next to a farmer's house in Texas.
两块碎片
Both were pieces of debris
都是来自同一个德尔塔II型火箭级
from the same stage of a Delta II rocket.
那是发射阶段的碎片
It's a piece of debris from a launch stage
在轨道上已有约9个月了
that was in orbit for about nine months
重新进入了美国和加拿大北部的上空
and re-entered over the northern part of the United States and Canada.
它落下 在周围留下了几块碎片
It came down and left several fragments of debris around.
这是最大的一块
This was the largest piece.
在加州埃尔塞贡多的航空航天公司
At the Aerospace Corporation in El Segundo, California,
科学家研究太空垃圾
scientists study space debris
来查明何种材料能挺过重返及其原因
to find out what materials survive re-entry and why,
如何最大限度减少未来的风险
and how to minimize future hazards.
这是把GPS卫星送入轨道的火箭残骸
This is remnants of a stage that put a GPS satellite into orbit.
是在沙特阿拉伯找到的
This was found in Saudi Arabia.
这个是用钛制作的
This one is made out of titanium,
那是熔点极高的材料
which is a very high-melting-point material,
那就是为何这东西能完好幸存下来的一个原因
and that's one reason why this one survived so nicely.
其次 这东西的速度
And this was traveling, again,
在击中地面时 或许在时速150英里左右
on the order of probably 150 miles an hour when it hit the ground.
为何物体会落回地球？
Why do objects fall back to Earth?
多数太空垃圾滞留在低地球轨道上
Most space debris resides in low Earth orbit,
离地约600英里的高度
approximately 600 miles above our planet's surface.
在太空中 物体可以滞留数千年
In space, objects can stay for tens to hundreds of years
因为那里没有空气阻力
because there's no air resistance.
但是它们最终会经历轨道衰减
But they will eventually undergo orbital decay.
它们会失去能量
They will lose energy
因为有很小的大气阻力
because there's very little atmospheric drag,
地球重力会把它们拽回大气层
and the Earth's gravity will tug them back down into its atmosphere.
卫星回落 有时很快 有时则要经过很长时间
Satellites fall back, sometimes quickly and sometimes over a long period,
只是因为它们开始接触到一点大气层时
simply because they begin to touch a little bit
大气层足以有一个增强的力道
of the atmosphere, enough of the atmosphere
加持较长的时间
that there's an increasing force over a long period of time.
较小的力道 坚持较长的时间
And that small force, acting over a long time,
基本上会将它们拉出轨道
will basically drag them out of orbit,
最终重新返回
and they will eventually re-enter.
大部分碎片在重返大气层时会燃烧和蒸发
Most debris burns up during atmospheric re-entry and vaporizes.
然而有些碎片出自较坚固的部件
However, some pieces are made of stronger components,
诸如不锈钢 钛 能够耐住高温
such as stainless steel and titanium, which can survive tremendous heat.
一旦越过了大气层的稠密区
Once below the dense regions of the atmosphere,
它们就落到地面上了
they literally free-fall to the ground.
它会以很低的速度落下
It'll hit at a very low velocity,
就是每秒150英尺或时速150英里 那个样子
say 150 feet per second or 150 miles an hour, something like that.
所以那就是问题所在
And so that's the problem.
所以你基本上是在把物体
So you're basically slowing something
在较短的时间里 从轨道速度减慢到静止
from an orbital speed down to essentially nothing in a relatively short time.
主发动机点火
Main engine start.
国际航天界现在对大多数物体规定了
The international space community now imposes
新的设计要求
new design requirements for most objects,
包括推进系统
including a propellant system
以确保控制重返在水上
to ensure controlled re-entries over water.
基本上 国际社会已同意
Basically, the international community has agreed
重返可接受的风险水平约为万分之一
that an acceptable level of risk for a re-entry is around one in 10,000.
那就是说 如果你有特定的重返1万次
That means that if you did a particular re-entry 10,000 times,
其可能性就是你会击中地面上的一个人
the likelihood is that you'll hit one person on the planet.
因此如果你超过了那个门槛
And so if you exceed that threshold,
目标就是把那块硬件重返到
the objective is that you should re-enter that piece of hardware
安全区域 比如大海里
into a safe area like the ocean.
但是新规则对已在太空中的数以千计的
But new guidelines won't have any effect
老碎片并没有任何效果
on the thousands of pieces of old debris already in space.
不幸的是 我们大量的太空物体还是
Unfortunately, we have a number of objects in space still
当时设计并没有围绕着那个要求进行的
which were not designed when that requirement was around.
它们仍然在缓缓降落
And they still are slowly coming down.
因此其中某些东西奏效尚有段时间
So it'll be a while before some of these things take effect.
那已不再是科幻
It's no longer a sci-fi fantasy.
天外及人为之物继续在从天而降
Extraterrestrial and manmade things continue to fall to Earth.
我们需要坚持不懈地搜索天空
We constantly need to search the skies
寻找那些会摧毁整个街区
for objects that could decimate a neighborhood,
整个世界乃至人类文明
even world and human civilization.